Hey, hey. What's up, my friend? So, in
today's video, I want to share with you
a trading system. In fact, it's a
Ballinger band trading system that has
generated
2,834% over the last 25 years. And I'll
give you the exact trading rules of this
trading systems, the setup, the entries,
the exits, the risk management, and
trading examples. So, you can see how
this works. And hopefully, you can use
the concepts, the strategies, the
insights, and apply it to your own
trading and get results. Sounds good
then let's get to
it. So first thing is the concept behind
this trading system and is is very
simple. In
fact almost all of my trading systems
that I trade the concepts are relatively
simple. If your trading system the
concept is too complicated chances are
you know you are curfew fitting or you
have something that probably doesn't
work in the live market. So most right
if not all of my trading systems the
concepts are very simple. So for this
system the concept is simple. We are
identifying stocks that are in an
uptrend. Okay, we are waiting waiting to
buy on a
pullback. Okay, if it's oversold. So,
you might be wondering Raina, you know,
how do I defi define a pullback? How do
I define when the stock is oversold?
Don't worry, we'll get to that shortly.
So, once the stock makes a pullback,
once it's oversold, we buy. Okay? And
when it makes a bounce higher, we sell,
thereby capturing this one swing over
here. So, in other words, this you can
treat this like a swing trading system.
Usually your trades are a few days,
right, and you're out of it. So let's
move on and talk about the rules of this
trading system, what markets we are
trading and stuff like that. So we are
trading stocks in the Russell 1000. This
means the largest 10,000 stocks in the
US stock market. The reason for this is
that these stocks are highly liquid. You
can buy and sell with relatively with
rel relative ease, right? Without much
slippages. Time frame is the daily time
frame. and risk management. This one is
important. 20% of your capital and a
maximum of five positions. What do I
mean by this? So whenever you know you
need to buy a stock, right, the next
logical question after the setup, after
the entry is how much stock to buy or
sell. So this is where your risk
management comes into play. Let's say if
you have a $100,000 trading capital and
you could know that you can only hold a
maximum of five stocks. So how much
money should you allocate to each stock?
20% right as what we have state over
here. So this means let's say you have a
valid trading setup opportunity on stock
A. What's the dollar value of stock A
you're going to buy? You're going to buy
$20,000 worth of stock A. Let's say you
have another trading setup on stock B.
How much dollar value of stock B? You're
going to buy another
$20,000. You're going to do this for a
maximum of five stocks. Because if you
were to buy all five stocks, then all
your $100,000 trading capital will be
used up and we are not using leverage.
So this is why we have a maximum
allocation of five stocks and 20% of our
capital allocated to each
stock. Next one, the juicy bits, the
exact trading rules.
Okay.
So you know the concept of the trading
system which I shared with you earlier.
But taking the concept to define it into
a setup the entries and exits requires
more than you know just a few a few
lines. So we're going to break this down
step by step. First one over here is how
we define the uptrend. The stock price
must be above the 200 day moving
average. Now some of you might be
wondering Raina is that the simple
moving average or the exponential moving
average or the weighted moving average?
The answer is it doesn't matter. Right?
The concept is what matter because you
can use a simple moving average, a
weighted blah blah blah. The end results
isn't really going to matter much
because that squiggly line on your chart
is more or less around the same place on
the chart regardless of whether you're
using exponential moving average
weighted or whatsoever. So the key thing
is that we want to make sure that the
stock price is above the 200 day 200 day
moving average. This is how we define
the
uptrend. So why do we want to buy stocks
in an uptrend? Reason is simple. Stocks
that are in an uptrend, they are likely
to continue going up higher. For
example, you're feeling a little bit
horny. You want to make love to your
wife. Are you going to pop the question,
are you going to hint to her when she's
in a good mood or in a bad mood? I think
logically speaking, all men is going to
say that they are going to approach
their wife when they are feeling in a
good mood, right? Not in a bad mood. So,
same thing when you want to buy stocks,
you want to profit from stock trading,
stock investing. Okay? Maybe not stock
investing, but stock trading. You want
to do so when the stock is already in an
uptrend because there's a good chance it
will continue higher and that's where
you can make
money. Second thing, the stock price
closes below the lower ballinger band.
So this is how we define a pullback. So
there are many ways to define a
pullback. Some people can use, you know,
RSI indicator 10 period RSI below 30,
below 20, etc. But in this case, we're
using the Ballinger band. So when the
stock price closes below the lower
Ballinger band, right? That's how we
define a pullback. And the settings for
the Ballinger band, you can just look
over here at the bottom. We're using a
20-day moving average and 2.5 standard
deviation. So once the stock price has
made a pullback, what's next? We're
going to place a 3% buy limit or order
to help us define that the stock is
temporarily oversold. So imagine this,
right? The I'll share with you some
examples later on, but let me just kind
of like use this over here. Stock price,
okay, makes a pullback. Okay, so let's
say at this point it has closes it
closed below the lower ballinger band
over here. So what we're looking for is
for the stock price to drop another 3%
the next day intraday basis so we can go
long. We're going to place a 3% buy
limit order. So we're going to get
filled somewhere about here. As the
stock price drops another 3% on an
intraday basis the next day. So once we
get filled you can imagine that we are
kind of buying on a falling knife. Yeah.
When there's a lot of fear in the
markets. So once we get filled on our
position now our setup is met, our entry
is met. When do we sell? When is our
exit? We will sell when the 2-day RSI
crosses above 50 or after 10 trading
days. So over here we have two part to
our exit. When the 2-day RSI crosses
above 50 or after 10 trading days. So
why is that two part to our exits? Most
of the time your exit right will happen
when the 2-day RSI crosses above 50. So
in other words, what's going to look
like on the chart is that we're going to
see a slight bounce up. Let's say this
the pullback over here. You could have a
slight bounce up higher, right? And over
here at this point is where the 2D RSI
crosses above 50 and then you sell the
stock. But there are times when the
stock price just doesn't bounce. In
fact, the moment you buy, it keeps
dropping lower and lower and lower. But
you still need to get out of the trade
eventually. You don't want to hold it,
you know, after it drops 70 80%. So this
is where the the stop loss, a timebased
stop loss comes into play. You hold it
for a maximum of 10 trading days. If
after 10 trading days, your 2D RSI is
still not met, your 2D RSI still hasn't
crossed above 50, you will still exit
the trade for a loss. And then the fifth
rule over here, so this is more of a
ranking of this system, right? Because
you're trading stocks in the Russell
10,000 and and there are potentially
thousand trading opportunities, right?
But it's unlikely you get thousand
trading opportunities, but sometimes you
can get, you know, 50 100 potential
trading setups, but you know, you can
only buy five stocks at the maximum. Why
five? because we mentioned behind over
here maximum of five positions. So now
how do you then decide which of the five
stocks you want to buy assuming that
criteria one to four are met. So this is
where we rank our stocks according to
their rate of change. In other words, we
want to buy the strongest stocks out
there. We want to buy the strongest
stocks that has increased the most in
price over the last 150 days. So this
how we narrow down filter down the list
of stocks to the top five strongest
stocks.
And yes right this is now the the rules
of this trading system. And because this
is a systematic approach this is an
objective trading system. This is what I
call systems trading. You can actually
back test this entire trading system.
And this is the results of it. 2834%
over the last 25 years. Right? So this
has you know has traded in the docom
bubble the 2008 financial crisis covid
Russia Ukraine war. You can see that it
has been consistently profitable over
the last two decades. If you want to
drill a little bit deeper, you can see
that over the last uh 25 years, annual
return is about 14% a year on average in
the long run. 66% winning rate, 33%
losing rate, average profit percentage
is about
4.1%. Average loss is 4.7% and a maximum
draw down of 27%. So this trading system
has a relatively high winning rate. The
so-called downside to it is that your
average profit is usually smaller than
your average loss. So if you look at it
from a risk-to-reward standpoint, you're
kind of like risking a dollar to make 80
cents, 85 cents there about. Okay. Now,
let me walk you through a chart example
so you can see how this works. So we
have one trading example over here. I'm
using the replay mode so you can, you
know, kind of like see how the criterias
are met. So remember, first thing first,
we're looking for the stock to be above
the 200 day moving average. So I'm just
going to change this to 200.
I like this to be black color because
that's just my preference even though I
just wasted three seconds of your life.
Okay, and there we have it. Right, I'm
going to bring out the 200 day moving
average. There you have it. The stock
price is above the 200 day moving
average. So, what's the second thing
we're looking for? For the stock price
to close below the lower Ballinger band.
So, I'm going to pull up my Ballinger
band.
Okay. Um I think it's this one probably.
Yeah. Okay. Okay, I'm just going to
change the settings to the one we are
using. Inputs 20 is correct, standard
deviation 2.5. And I'm going to press
okay. And there you have it.
Right now you can see that the stock
price has
closed rather the stock price has closed
below the lower Ballinger band. Now
what's the next thing? If you recall the
next thing is then to place a
3% buy limit order. And now for this I
need my calculator.
Okay, there you have it. My trusty
calculator that I use, right, whenever I
calculate position size for my trading
systems. So, what is the closing price
on this day? The closing price on this
day is
$27.71. So, what you're going to do is
just take
27.71 multiply by 0.97 to know what is
the buy limit order price that we need
to place it at. So 27.71
ultiply by.97 gives us
26.88. Okay,
26.88. If I round it off to the highest
the the higher decimal place, 26.88. So
what you're going to do is that assuming
now the market is closed. The next day
you're going to place a buy limit order
which is 20% of your trading capital at
26.88. So I'm just going to use this
tool. Okay, let's get the horizontal
one.
Let's put it to green, right? To signal
our entry trigger at
26.88.
Okay. So, next day if the market touches
this green line, we would have gotten
filled on this trade. This would have
met all our criteria of this Ballinger
band trading
system. Okay. Boom. You can see over
here next day we had a we had a gap down
lower. Clearly, we would have gotten
filled on this trade. In fact, we
probably got filled at a better price
than what we expected. probably around
26.6 and we have gotten filled on this
trade. Now the next thing is when do we
sell the this this uh this uh position.
So remember our exit has two parts to
it. When the 2-day RSI crosses above 50
or after 10 trading days. So in this
case I'm going to pull out the RSI
indicator. Again the default settings on
Trading View. It's it's enough just
change the settings two period. I don't
need the the SMA and stuff like that.
Okay. And I just uh I can actually
remove this. Not needed. and press okay.
So what we're looking for is for the
2-day RSI which is this value over here
which is currently now 0.95 to be above
50 because for that to happen right the
market need to actually close higher. So
let's see what happens right not yet
right now the value is47 as you can see
over here the value here is 0.47 so our
exit criteria is not
met 15.62 62 not
yet 13.36 not yet boom you see this over
here
71.53 okay so this now means that our ex
exit criteria is met and we need to exit
this trade and when do we exit we exit
at the next day open so when the stock
price opens the next day over
here we would exit this trade and in
this case it's probably going to be a
losing trade but it's uh it's irrelevant
right because this trading system we
want to back test it and run it over
thousands of trade and not just you know
based the quality based on the
performance on the trading system just
based on one chart doesn't quite make
sense it's random now I'll do another
example so you can understand how this
trading system works but I'll go a bit
faster since you're already kind of
familiar with it so first thing first
the stock price is above the 200 day
moving average so it's in in an uptrend
good second thing is we're looking for
the stock price to close below the lower
ballinger band as you can see over here
it did great so next thing we're going
to do is to place a 3% % buy limit order
to see if we can get filled on the trade
the next day. So, you know this stock
price, the closing price in this case,
it's
113.713.7. What we're going to do is
multiply by 0.97 to know what price to
place our buy limit order. And in this
case, the price is
110 or just
110.29. Okay, 110.29.
So, we're going to place a buy limit
order at
110.29. So, I'm just going to get this
one out.
110.29. Okay. So, this means the next
day if the stock price touches this
green line, which is where our buy limit
order is, we would get filled on the
trade. And of course, we got filled on
the trade because this is a cherry pig
chart to illustrate to you how this
works. Now, once you're filled on the
trade, when do you sell? You sell when
the 2-day RSI crosses above 50 or after
10 trading days. So if you pay attention
to the RSI values right now, currently
it's about
7.7. Let's see. Now it's
five. Now it's 50.4. Great. It has meet
our exit criteria. But now the market is
closed. When can we exit the trade?
Well, do it when the market opens the
next day, which is boom over here. So in
this case, the stock price opened at
this level over here. You would have
exit this trade for a profit. Okay. What
I've just shared with you is what we
call a mean reversion trading system and
it's one of the concepts, proven
concepts, right, that I use in my own
live trading account. So, of course,
there are other concepts like trend
following. How do you know right massive
trends in the market and it's something
that I'm not able to cover in this video
because I want to keep it related to the
Ballinger band trading system. So if you
want to learn the concepts about trend
following then what you can do is to
actually go over here and download this
guide called the essential guide to
systems trading. Reason being is just go
to my website over here
tradingwithra.com just scroll down a
little bit and you'll see this guide
right this uh black color sexyl looking
guide. Just click this orange button and
enter your email address and I'll send
it to your email for free. So what
happens is that in this guide I will
share with you the concept of trend
following. how you can actually write
massive trends in the market. And to
take things a step further, I will also
give you the exact trend following rules
so you can understand how the concepts
and strategies work. And not just that,
right? I will also teach you the
framework how I go about developing
profitable trading systems that has a
high chance to work, right? Even if you
have tried everything else and failed.
So this is the framework that I actually
use to develop till today, right? Seven
trading system that I trade in my live
account. So again, if you want to learn
the exact framework, if you want to
learn more about trend following, how to
apply trend following to write massive
trends, a simple trend following system
that works, then this guide, the
essential guide to systems trading is
what you need. I'll put the link below
this video or you can go directly to
tradinger.com and download a free copy.
So with that said, I wish you good luck,
good trading, and I will talk to you
soon.